<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TIL on Jett&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/til/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TIL on Jett&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Jett Chen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:47:56 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why archive.org can&#39;t prove the authenticity of their snapshots</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/insecure-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:47:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/insecure-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Recently, a federal judge ruled against the Internet Archive in their mission to preserve ebooks. While this doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to do with the WayBack Machine, it led me to wonder: why do we need a centralized platform to take and share website snapshots in the first place? Why not let users take them themselves and share them around the internet?&#xA;The answer to this question seems obvious at first glance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: How shodan takes screenshots of computers</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/shodan-rdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 19:20:46 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/shodan-rdp/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have been playing around with shodan images, a service provided by shodan that aggregates screenshots of accesible videofeeds over the internet of things, including a lot of windows login screens and webcams.&#xA;The catch is, while they provide the screenshot for the users, shodan provides absolutely no hints as of how they obtained the screenshot.&#xA;Shodan claims that they grabbed those screenshots based as the RDP service is exposed to the internet, but when I tried to access the remote desktops with Microsoft Remote Desktop, it immediately prompted me for a username and password, which I do not have.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Burpsuite</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/til-burp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 23:13:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/til-burp/</guid>
      <description>About: TIL TIL stands for &amp;ldquo;Today I Learned,&amp;rdquo; and I plan to write a TIL post whenever I discover something interesting. It could be related to anything: from technology to life.&#xA;This is inspired by 100daystooffload and various TIL posts I found over the internet. This can motivate me to keep finding interesting things to learn and experience, improve my writing a little bit, and, most importantly, be an intriguing read.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
